Guide to the Robert J. Cox papers, 1879-2010 RL.11794
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1950-2004; 3
  - Journals and Personal Notes, 1977-1979; 2
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Notes about threats, kidnappings, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Writings by Robert Cox, 1965-2002; 3
    The Writings by Robert Cox subseries consists of individual published pieces written by Robert Cox. Drafts of published pieces are arranged with their published counterpart. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    - Argentina: An Overview by Robert Cox, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Articles about Jacobo Timmerman, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Articles by Cox in U.S. press, 1965-1976 (Box 5)
    - Disappeared Journalists - Incomplete Draft, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Draft of article about La Tablada garrison attack, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Harpers (article by Cox) Argentina: Souring on the Democratic Dream, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Hemisphere Overview Committee on Freedom of the Press and Information, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Introduction to A Year with Two Winters by Martin Robbins, n.d. (Box 5)
    - A Jamesian love story by Robert Cox, n.d. (Box 5)
    - La Industria de Chiclayo, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Raúl Alfonsín removes the noose of terror. Argentina's Democratic Miracle, 1984 (Box 5)
    - The Sound of One Hand Clapping, 1980 (Box 5)
      Contains drafts of The Sound of One Hand Clapping: A Preliminary Study of the Argentine Press in a Time of Terror, which was written for the Wilson Center in Washington D.C.
    - The Souring of the Argentine Dream: Democracy meets the Red Queen, 1985 (Box 5)
      Written by Robert Cox; published in Harper's magazine.
    - Total Terrorism: Argentina, 1969-1979 (Box 5)
      An excerpt written by Cox from the edited volume Terrorism, Legitimacy and Power: The Consequences of Political Violence.
    - About Robert Cox, 1976-2002 (Box 6)
    - Argentina Turns a Corner, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Cox Articles for Foreign Media, 1964-2002 (Box 6)
    - Grenada, 1984-1988 (Box 6)
    - Grenada - by R. Cox, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Harper's Article, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Interview with V.S. Naipaul, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Lesdesma; Fraud and Peronism, 1985-1996 (Box 6)
    - Writings by R. Cox (?), 1977-1997 (Box 6)
    - News and Courier articles, 1982-1985 (Oversize-box 8)
    - News and Courier articles, 2001-2002 (Oversize-box 8)
    - Review of Peron and the Enigmas of Argentina, 1987 (Oversize-box 8)
  - Writings by Others, 1969-2004; 4
    The Writings by Others subseries consists of written pieces authored by individuals other than Robert Cox. Some pieces have annotations. Subjects represented in works include journalism, Brazil, the Buenos Aires Herald, the Dirty War/El Proceso, U.S. human rights policy, social life in Argentina, U.S. - Argentina relations, and human rights abuses in Latin America.
    - Annotated section of Dirty Secrets, Dirty War (Box 5)
    - Anti-Semitism in Argentina by Chris Hedges, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Argentina in Agony by Stephen Kinzer, 1978 (Box 5)
    - Argentina: Land of Promise, Land of Pain, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Argentina - A Smoldering Volcano, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Articles about Robert Cox, 1980-1983 (Box 5)
    - Article by Henry Raymont, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Brasil: Seis Años de Desarrollo Acelerado by Arnaldo T. Musich, n.d. (Box 5)
    - The Case of the Disappeared by Jerome J. Shestack, 1980 (Box 5)
    - A Case of Torture Dean Farisani, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Conference papers-Latin America, 1988-1995 (Box 5)
      Conference papers written by others.
    - Consejo de Europea Comité de Ministros Del Comité de Ministros a los Estados Miembros Sobre El Lenguaje de Odio, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Coverage of Human Rights Abuses in the Buenos Aires Daily Press During Argentinas Dirty War, 1976-1979: A Rule of Silence and Its Exception, 1987 (Box 5)
      A dissertation written by Kristin Anne Goss in consultation with Robert Cox.
    - El caso de Robert Cox: otro silencio en Argentina by Andrew Graham-Yoll, 1980 (Box 5)
    - El Herald y Las Víctimas de La Última Dictadura Militar (1976-1982), n.d. (Box 5)
      This section appears to be part of a book or edited volume with pieces by César L. Díaz, Mario J. Giménez, and Marta Passaro.
    - El Herald y Su Particular Compromiso Frente a Un Tema Tabú: Los Derechos Humanos Durante La Dictadura, n.d. (Box 5)
    - El lector de palabras, palabras, palabras. por Santiago Bullrich, 1982 (Box 5)
    - El Valor de la prensa by Uki Goñi, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Excerpt from book written by César L. Díaz, Mario J. Giménez, and Marta Passaro. (Box 5)
    - Extensive Description of the Argentine Documentary Nunca Más by M.L. Freund, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Gail Prensky: Existence Denied, 2001 (Box 5)
      The file also includes correspondence between Prensky and Cox.
    - Gaps, Metaphors and Modern Fiction: A Study of Indeterminancy in the Modern Novel., 1981 (Box 5)
    - Human Rights, Culture and The Problem of Justice by Joseph P. Fitzpatrick, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Human Rights Diplomacy: The Carter Administration and the Southern Cone, 1982 (Box 5)
      Written by Roberta Cohen, published in Human Rights Quarterly.
    - Human Rights and the U.N. Committee on Crime Prevention and Control by Roger S. Clark, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Inhabited by History: Charleston, S.C. by Josephine Humphreys, 1989 (Box 5)
    - The Inner Ring Mentality by Edwin A. Lahey, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Introductory Remarks for Special Symposium to Honor Andrei Sakharov by Sidney D. Drell, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Is Bribery A Moral Issue by John T. Noonan, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Jornadas Sobre Futuro Politico de la Argentina Part 1, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Jornadas Sobre Futuro Politico de la Argentina Part 2, 1977 (Box 5)
    - Julia, a Latin American Woman, n.d. (Box 5)
    - La Desilusión de los No Socios Con El Proceso (1976-1982) (Box 5)
    - Latin America: The Democratic Option, 1987 (Box 5)
    - La Visita Indeseada de La Cidh: Un Caso de Periodismo Pendular (Box 5)
    - A Lonely Herald, J. Peterson, 2004 (Box 5)
      A piece written by Jeremy Peterson.
    - Manfred Schönfeld, 1980-1981 (Box 5)
    - Must God Create the Best? by Robert Adams, 1972 (Box 5)
    - A New Approach to Foreign Aid and Economic Development by David T. Kleinman (Box 5)
    - Not Their Finest Hour by Alex Rodriguez - Giovo, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Novel proposal (fragments), n.d. (Box 5)
    - Nueva Escuela Mas y Mejor Educacion Para Todos, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Open Letter on Issues of Race at Harvard, 1981 (Box 5)
    - Politica Armada en La Columna Del Herald (1974-1982), n.d. (Box 5)
    - Poema Robertiano, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Pretérito imperfecto por Jorge Elías, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Regime Terrorism and the press in Latin America, 1984 (Box 5)
      Two drafts of the same presentation given at the Colby Social Science Division Colloqium on Terrorism from January 9-10th 1984 at Colby College in Waterville, Maine.
    - Robert Cox: An Editor In Danger, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Rodrigo Rojas 1967-1986 Killed in Chile by David Remnick (Box 5)
    - The Siege of the Argentine Jews by Robert Weisbrot and The Solitude of Jacobo Timerman, 1981 (Box 5)
    - The Sporting Scene Ar-gen-tina! by Alastair Reid, 1982 (Box 5)
    - The Strange Life and Stranger Death of David Graiver by Anthony Haden - Guest, 1979 (Box 5)
    - Student Conference Papers, 1982-2002 (Box 5)
    - Student Conference Papers, 1984 (Box 5)
    - Testimony of Sofonias Cisneros Leiva, 1985 (Box 5)
    - The Times of Arnaud: A News Legend Fights World War III Against the Dread Washington Post by Edwin Diamond, 1985 (Box 5)
    - U.S. Drug Policy: A Bad Export by Ethan A. Nadelmann, 1988 (Box 5)
    - U.S. Human Rights Initiatives Concerning Argentina, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Amnesty International - Argentina The Attack on the Third Infantry Regiment Barracks at La Tablada, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Annotated Draft of Dirty Secrets, Dirty War Chapter 3, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Article by John J. O'Connor, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Britain Wants Back in Latin Trade Picture by Penny Lernoux, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Habeas Corpus a Dios!, 1979 (Box 6)
      A pamphlet created by the family of Jorge Marcelo Dyszel about the disappearance of him and his wife Mirtha Nelida Schwalb de Dyszel. The pamphlet appears to have been sent to Cox because it contains an annotation on the front cover that says al Sr Roberto Cox.
    - How Argentina Won Its War Against Leftist Terrorism, 1982 (Box 6)
      Written by Virginia Prewett and William R. Mizelle.
    - La Libanizacion Argentina by J. Iglesias Rouco, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Las Fuerzas Armadas y El Estado Autoritario del Cono Sur de America Guillermo A. Donnell, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Manuscript by Andrea Yaryura, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Partial Draft of A Single Numberless Death by Nora Strejilevich, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Partial Manuscript of H. Kahn on López Rega, Perón and the 1974-1976 years (Box 6)
    - Proof - Argentines oppose bon vivant president, despite recent religious turn by Sam Dillon, 1991 (Box 6)
    - Student Conference Papers, pt. 2, 1982-2002 (Box 6)
    - Violaciones de los Derechos Humanos bajo el Gobierno Constitutional en Argentina, 1986 (Box 6)
      Written by Federico E. Alvarez Rojas.
    - Periodistas, 1980 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Editorials, 1963-1990; 1
    The Editorial subseries consists of editorials published in the Buenos Aires Herald and the News and Courier. Most were written by Cox. Topics of the editorials include kidnappings, terrorism, Central America, Juan Carlos Onganía, Juan Perón, Raúl Alfonsín, Arturo Umberto Illia, Arturo Frondizi, and Cuba. The contents of the subseries have been arranged either chronologically or by subject matter.
    - The Argentine Dream - Proof by Robert Cox, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Articles for News and Courier, Buenos Aires Herald, 1983-2001 (Box 6)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1973-1979 (Box 6)
    - Cuba trip Editorials, 1990 (Box 6)
    - Illia - Frondizi, 1963 (Box 6)
    - John Paul II visit to Central America, 1983 (Box 6)
    - Murdered Priests, 1970-1976 (Box 6)
    - Ongania, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Peron, Government and Military Organizing, 1963-1972 (Box 6)
    - Editorials, 1976-1977 (Oversize-box 7)
    - Pope John Paul II Visit to Nicaragua, 1983 (Oversize-box 7)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1965-1969 (Oversize-box 9)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1972 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1973 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1974 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1975 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1975-1976 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1976 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1977 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1978 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials, 1979-1989 (Oversize-box 12)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials Part 1, undated (Oversize-box 13)
      Most undated clippings appear to be from the 1970s.
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials Part 2, undated (Oversize-box 13)
    - Buenos Aires Herald Editorials Part 3, undated (Oversize-box 13)
- Publications, 1879-2006; 4
  The Publications series consists of full length magazines, reports or other publications collected by Robert Cox. Many have articles written by Robert Cox. Many of the Argentine publications are scarce, including El Diario del Juicio. The topics covered by the publications include international human rights and Argentine politics. The subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - AAAS Clearinghouse Report on Science and Human Rights, 1983 (Box 2)
  - American Univerisities Field Staff Special Report - The First-World Third-World Understanding Gap, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Amnesty International Handbook, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Argentine News, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Argentine Postwar Economic Policies by Javier Villanueva, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Attacks on the Press 1987 A Worldwide Survey Committee to Protect Journalists, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Buenos Aires en el año 2080 historia verosimil por A. Sioen, 1879 (Box 2)
  - C.G.T., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Diplomats and Terrorists: What Works, What Doesn't, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Discusión quincenario de política y economía, 1975 (Box 2)
  - El Infierno También Fue Argentino, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Envio Publicación del Instituto Histórico Centroamericano y de la Universidad Centroamericana, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Freedom at Issue, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Human Rights Internet Reporter April-June 1983, Volume 8 Nos. 4 and 5 (Box 2)
  - IAPA News, 1987-1992 (Box 2)
  - In the Public Interest, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Inside Cuba A Special Report of the Cuba Roundtable, 1990 (Box 2)
  - The International League for Human Rights, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
  - International Terrorism: An Inquiry into Contemporary Political Violence A Resource Book, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Las Mil Caras de Pinochet, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Latin America a weekly political report, 1976 (Box 2)
  - A Los Pueblos de America Latina, n.d. (Box 2)
  - The New Republic, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Nieman Reports, 1979; 2006 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlets, 1979-1981 (Box 2)
    Includes La Prensa Diario Libre de Panamá and Comment.
  - Para La Historia del Periodismo, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Periodicals, 1963-1968 (Box 2)
    Includes issues of Primera Plana and Confirmado.
  - Periodicals, 1971-1978 (Box 2)
    Includes issues of Extra, Somos, and Carta Politica.
  - Periodicals, 1980-1984 (Box 2)
  - Periodicals, 1985-1988 (Box 2)
  - Periodicals, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
  - Preface, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Press in Argentina 1973-8 Andrew Graham-Yooll, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Primera Plana, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Salvadoran Democracy Project, Freedom in the World, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Scientists and Human Rights in Argentina Since 1976, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Second InterAmerican Dialogue Report, 1984 (Box 2)
  - The St. Michael's Meeting Argentine-American Forum, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Uruguay's Military Physicians Cogs in a System of State Terror by Maxwell Gregg Bloche, 1987 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Human Rights Policy: An AIUSA Position Paper, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Boletin del Frente de Liberación Homosexual de la Argentina, 1976 (Box 6)
  - Cuba Facts: A Resource Document for the United States Congress Prepared by the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Cuba in the Nineties, 1991 (Box 6)
  - El Montonero and Partido Autentico, 1976 (Box 6)
  - International League for Human Rights Annual Review, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - A Year with Two Winters by Martin Robbins, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Construccion National (full issue) Julio-Diciembre, 1974 (Oversize-box 8)
  - El Diario del Juicio Part 1 and 2, 1985 (Oversize-box 8)
  - El Diario del Juicio Part 3 and 5, 1985 (Oversize-box 8)
  - El Diario del Juicio Part 8, 9, 11, 1985 (Oversize-box 8)
  - El Diario del Juicio Part 12 and 13, 1985 (Oversize-box 8)
  - The New York Times Magazine - Return to Argentina by Jacobo Timerman, 1984 (Oversize-box 8)
  - Porqué, No. 1-4, 1988 (Oversize-box 8)
  - Porqué, No. 5-9; 1988 (Oversize-box 8)
  - Buenos Aires Herald Centennial Edition, 1976 (Oversize-box 9)
  - Buenos Aires Herald - British Royal Visit, 1962 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Buenos Aires Herald - Edited Copy Proof, 1968 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Nuevo Gobierno and La Opinión, 1976 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Historia de Peron, n.d. (Oversize-box 16)
  - Seran Asesinados - Marchar, 1974 (Oversize-box 16)